<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><metadata>
    <idinfo>
        <citation>
            <citeinfo>
                <origin/>
                <title>Utah Points of Diversion</title>
                <onlink>https://services.arcgis.com/ZzrwjTRez6FJiOq4/arcgis/rest/services/PODView/FeatureServer</onlink>
            </citeinfo>
        </citation>
        <descript>
            <abstract>The Point of Diversion feature class is a complete record of point of diversion locations taken from the Division's day to day operating database. The database is a complete record with the following exceptions:1) The Division's point of diversion referencing policy includes a provision which allows some point of diversion locations to be described more as areas (Point-to-Point Filings) than discrete points. Point to point filings are usually limited to stock watering rights. They are represented  by a discrete point which is located within the area covered by the point to point description.2) Utah State Law required applications to divert surface water to be filed with the State Engineer after 1903 and groundwater after 1935. There may be existing diversions which began prior to those dates which are not included in the Division of Water Right records. The Division becomes aware of these rights and includes these rights in it's records when the user submits a statement of water user claim either pursuant to an adjudication or to establish there is a water right under which the State Engineer is to take action.3) Data in the Division of Water Rights database was entered over an eight year period from paper files maintained by the office. Data entered in the database has been subsequently verified by staff. However, errors are occasionally detected in the database as a result of entry operations either from current staff activities or the original entry project. The Division makes an ongoing effort to maintain the database free of errors and omissions, however users of the data are responsible to verify it is suitable for their purpose. The Division appreciates and encourages users to promptly disclose any inconsistencies detected in the data to Division staff who will make every effort to correct any errors discovered.</abstract>
            <purpose>Points of diversion from Water Rights database. The points are generated daily from basic information in the tabular database</purpose>
        </descript>
        <keywords>
            <theme>
                <themekt>None</themekt>
                <themekey>Points of Diversion</themekey>
                <themekey>SGID</themekey>
                <themekey>Utah</themekey>
                <themekey>Water</themekey>
                <themekey>Water Rights</themekey>
                <themekey>Utah Division of Water Rights</themekey>
            </theme>
        </keywords>
        <accconst>None</accconst>
        <useconst>There are no warranties with regard to the use of the data sets associated with the Division of Water Rights. No accuracy warranty is made by the Utah Division of Water Rights.</useconst>
        <datacred>Utah Division of Water Rights,</datacred>
    </idinfo>
    <eainfo>
        <detailed>
            <attr>
                <attrlabl>WRNUM</attrlabl>
                <attrdef>Water Right Number</attrdef>
            </attr>
            <attr>
                <attrlabl>CHEXNUM</attrlabl>
                <attrdef>Change or Exchange Number</attrdef>
            </attr>
            <attr>
                <attrlabl>TYPE</attrlabl>
                <attrdef>TYPE OF RIGHT
ABANDONED WELL: well whose purpose and use have been permanently discontinued.
DRAIN: Excess collection/control system (surface or groundwater) from which a point of diversion maybe established
POINT TO POINT: Point To Point diversions are not developed points of diversion. The reference is to a stream segment from which stock may drink. Often designated in 40 acre parcels.
REDIVERSION: Diversion point, which diverts water which was previously diverted and released upstream. Usually associated with reservoir storage.
RETURN: Point where water that has been non-consumptively used is returned back to the natural stream.
SPRING: Concentrated discharge of ground water coming out at the surface as flowing water
SURFACE: Streams, rivers, creeks, any water above ground
UNDERGROUND: Wells, tunnels, sumps, and undgrd drains</attrdef>
            </attr>
            <attr>
                <attrlabl>SUMMARY_ST</attrlabl>
                <attrdef>Status of Application
A = Approved
P = Perfected: proof filed, right certificated
T = terminated, lapsed, expired, abandoned, etc
U = Unapproved</attrdef>
            </attr>
            <attr>
                <attrlabl>STATUS</attrlabl>
                <attrdef>Status = combination of:
DOCUMENT TYPE
ABAN = Abandoned
ADEC = Adjudication Decree
ADV = Adverse Use Claim: if a person was using water claimed by another party for 5 yrs+, with no protest from original claimant, water became the users.
APPL = Appl to Appropriate
DEC = Decree: judgemental decision on a civil action in a district court
DIL = Diligence Claim: claim on surface water filed prior to 1903
FIXD = Temp Applications (greater than 1 year)
TEMP = Temp Applications (1 year or less)
UGWC = Undergrd Water Claim: undgrd water in use prior to 1935
STATUS
APP = Approved
CERT = Certificated: official documentation serving as evidence of a perfected water right
DIS = Disallowed
EXP = Expired (temp water rights only)
LAP = Permanently Lapsed: failed to show proof w/in allotted time
LIT = Litigation: pending court action on a right
NPR = No Proof Required: applications filed from 1940's to 1961 for 0.015 cfs or less were not required to submit proof
NUSE = A NON-USE Application has been filed.
REJ = Rejected
TERM = Terminated
UNAP = Unapproved
WD=Withdrawn
WUC(S)=Water User's Claim (Signed)</attrdef>
            </attr>
            <attr>
                <attrlabl>PRIORITY</attrlabl>
                <attrdef>date on which the application fee was paid</attrdef>
            </attr>
            <attr>
                <attrlabl>USES</attrlabl>
                <attrdef>D = Domestic 
I = Irrigation
M = Municipal
O = Other
P = Power
S = Stockwatering
X = Mining</attrdef>
            </attr>
            <attr>
                <attrlabl>CFS</attrlabl>
                <attrdef>Flow in cubic feet per second</attrdef>
            </attr>
            <attr>
                <attrlabl>ACFT</attrlabl>
                <attrdef>Area measured in acre-feet.</attrdef>
            </attr>
            <attr>
                <attrlabl>LOCATION</attrlabl>
                <attrdef>Direction (N or S)
Distance (feet)
Direction (E or W)
Distance (feet)
Section corner (NW,NE,SW,SE,N4,E4,S4,W4)
Base &amp; Meridian Allowable 2-character codes:
6S=Sixth Principle (CO,WY)
BO=Boise B&amp;M (ID)
GS=Gila&amp;Salt River B&amp;M (AZ)
MD=Mt. Diablo B&amp;M (NV)
NM=New Mexico Principle (CO,NM)
SL=Salt Lake B&amp;M (UT)
US=Uintah Special B&amp;M (UT:{Duchesne, Uintah, Utah, &amp; Wasatch Counties})
Township: number from 1 to 44 followed by "N" or "S"
Range: number from 1 to 26 followed by "E" or "W"
Section: number from 1 to 36</attrdef>
            </attr>
            <attr>
                <attrlabl>WIN</attrlabl>
                <attrdef>Well Identification Number</attrdef>
            </attr>
            <attr>
                <attrlabl>OWNER</attrlabl>
                <attrdef>First Owner Listed On Right</attrdef>
            </attr>
            <attr>
                <attrlabl>SOURCE</attrlabl>
                <attrdef>Source of Supply</attrdef>
            </attr>
        </detailed>
    </eainfo>
    <metainfo>
        <metd>20201202</metd>
        <metc>
            <cntinfo>
                <!--no contact person or organization name available-->
            </cntinfo>
        </metc>
        <metstdn>FGDC Content Standard for Digital Geospatial Metadata</metstdn>
        <metstdv>FGDC-STD-001-1998</metstdv>
        <mettc>local time</mettc>
    </metainfo>
</metadata>
