<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><metadata>
    <idinfo>
        <citation>
            <citeinfo>
                <title>Map</title>
            </citeinfo>
        </citation>
        <descript>
            <abstract>Currently (2020), this dataset represents approximately 1,289 culinary water suppliers. Some public community suppliers have been split at county boundaries for accounting purposes.  These include public community, public non-community (transient), self-supplied industry (non-transient), and non-public water suppliers. This feature class includes system boundaries that are historical and no longer active. It also includes some systems that are outside the state. Historical and outside the state systems can be filtered using the ENDYEAR and STATE fields, respectively. SYSTEMTYPE = 'C' (Community) AND ENDYEAR IN (2019) will give currently active public community suppliers within the state. Supplier types can be further filtered using the SYSTEMTYPE field. These boundaries are derived from many different sources. They include spatial data received directly from the supplier, municipal boundaries, phone call descriptions of service areas, printed maps that had hand-drawn boundaries that were then digitized, etc.</abstract>
            <purpose>This dataset attempts to represent the culinary water suppliers service area boundaries for the State of Utah, with a small selection of suppliers in Idaho and Wyoming represented as well.  The suppliers in Idaho and Wyoming are present due to their involvement in the Bear River Drainage Basin.</purpose>
        </descript>
        <keywords>
            <theme>
                <themekt>None</themekt>
                <themekey>Utah</themekey>
                <themekey>AGRC</themekey>
                <themekey>SGID</themekey>
                <themekey>cloud</themekey>
                <themekey>water</themekey>
                <themekey>culinary</themekey>
                <themekey>potable</themekey>
                <themekey>systems</themekey>
                <themekey>suppliers</themekey>
                <themekey>retail</themekey>
                <themekey>public</themekey>
                <themekey>boundaries</themekey>
                <themekey>community</themekey>
                <themekey>non-community</themekey>
                <themekey>self-supplied</themekey>
                <themekey>municipal</themekey>
                <themekey>industrial</themekey>
                <themekey>service</themekey>
                <themekey>areas</themekey>
            </theme>
        </keywords>
        <accconst>None</accconst>
        <useconst>CC BY-SA  These boundaries or service areas are not legal descriptions, and are meant to generally represent service areas. No claim is made regarding boundary accuracy, and the data should be used with that understanding. This dataset may be shared, so long as sources and time relevance are cited. Be aware that this dataset is a work in progress, and does receive updates on at least an annual basis. For reference use only. Although this product represents the work of natural resource professionals, the Utah Department of Natural Resources, makes no warranty, expressed or implied, regarding its suitability for a particular use. The Utah Department of Natural Resources, shall not be liable under any circumstances for any direct, indirect, special, incidental, or consequential damages with respect to claims by users of this product.</useconst>
        <datacred>Utah Division of Water Resources, Utah Department of Natural Resources, (Data Steward), Utah Automated Geographic Reference Center, Utah Department of Technology Services, Utah Division of Water Rights, Utah Department of Natural Resources, Utah Division of Drinking Water, Utah Department of Environmental Quality, Culinary Water Suppliers around the state</datacred>
    </idinfo>
    <metainfo>
        <metstdn>FGDC Content Standard for Digital Geospatial Metadata</metstdn>
        <metstdv>FGDC-STD-001-1998</metstdv>
        <mettc>local time</mettc>
    </metainfo>
</metadata>
